#### Contact

yosh.rawat@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/yogesh-rawat-23820866 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Java

J2EE Application Development JavaScript

### Languages

English (Professional Working) Hindi (Professional Working)

### Certifications

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

### Honors-Awards

Spot Award

# Yogesh Rawat

Analyst at DBS Bank

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

## Summary

**Experienced Resource** 

Completed B.tech in Computers from Roorkee Institute Of Technologies, Roorkee and the then joined CDAC-ACTS (Advanced Computing Training School, the premier R&D organization of the Department of Electronics and Information Technology (DeitY)) to meet the ever-increasing skilled manpower requirements of the Information Communication Technologies (ICT) industry.

During engineering days I learnt basic skill-set required to survive

in IT industry, but I got to know my passion, place and the real application of knowledge in IT industry after joining CDAC. There I learnt efficient programming skills after knowing how and why they are required and what purpose they serve in real life.

An AWS Certified Developer, I'm a proficient Software Engineer with extensive experience in Software Design & Development of Enterprise and Cloud-based web Applications using CORE JAVA & J2EE technology. Extensively worked in development of microservices with Spring & Spring Boot Framework and Spring Cloud.

### Knowledge In:

# AWS Stack: EC2, AWS Lambda, S3, DynamoDB, CloudWatch, AWS CLI, CloudFormation, SES, SNS, SQS, Kinesis, IAM, Cloud9

# Programming & Scripting languages: Java, Unix, Shell Scripting

# Framework : Spring Framework. Spring cloud ,Spring Security.

# Development Notebooks and IDE: STS , Eclipse and Jupyter Notebook

# Relational & NOSQL Databases: Mariadb, Oracle,

MySQL, Cassandra

# Versioning Control & DevOps Toolset: JIRA, GIT, Confluence, Wiki, Jenkins, Gitlab CI

# Container Orchestration: Docker & kubernetes

# Knowledge of Apache Drill, Kafka and Apache Ignite

Page 1 of 2

# Experience

DBS Bank Analyst April 2017 - Present Hyderabad Area, India

Oracle
Application Engineer
April 2015 - April 2017 (2 years 1 month)
Hyderabad Area, India

Happiest Minds Technologies Software Engineer March 2013 - April 2015 (2 years 2 months) Bengaluru Area, India

## Education

Sunbeam InfoTech
PG Diploma, Diploma in Advance Computing · (2012 - 2013)

Roorkee Institue of Technology

Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Computer Science and

Engineering · (2007 - 2011)